A Guide to the Rockefeller University records, Faculty-Student records, Subject Files FA1330
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University records, Faculty-Student records, Subject Files
1941-1977
1957-1970
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University
Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
FA1330
0.7 Cubic Feet 2 boxes, 1 letter document box and 1 half-letter box,
Arrangement
Alphabetical by subject, with each file further arranged chronologically.
Scope and Contents
An assortment of material from the Office of the Registrar that originated from the offices of various academic administration.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
File Plan
Former Classification: I 370.3
- Administration, 1956-1977 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Copies of appointment notifications, change of address, etc.
- American Association of University Professors, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Report on Academic Salaries, 1969-1970
- American Association of University Women, 1962-1964 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Listings by year of women receiving advanced degrees.
- Awards for Graduate Study and Research, 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Published by Education Division of Canadian Bureau of Statistics
- College Facts Chart, 1961-1965, 1967-1968, 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Published by National Beta Club from reports by individual institutions
- Commission on the Future of Higher Education (The Carnegie Foundation), 1968, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Compliance Reports, 1967, 1968, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Reports required under the Civil Rights Act for educational institutions receiving or seeking Federal Aid. Required by HEW but filed with the University of the State of New York, State Education Department, Bureau of Statistical Services.
- Consultants, 1956-1958, 1960-1976 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Lists and copies of appointment letters to consultants on Hospital staff.
- Fellowships - NIH Post Doctoral, 1956-1962 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Fulbright Grants, 1962, 1968-1970 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Correspondence from the Committee on International Exchange of Persons
- Guests, 1965 December-1973 September (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Letters confirming arrangements.
- Institute of International Education (IIE), 1958-1975 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Jane Coffin Childs Memorial Fund for Medical Research, 1943-1951 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Correspondence dealing with use of funds to support research.
- Navy, 1941-1947 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Copies of correspondence between T. M. Rivers, H. S. Gasser and officers of US Navy, T. Debvoise to arrange contract agreement for treatment of Rockefeller Institute Hospital of Navy men during World War II. Includes photo of presentation in 1947 of Certificate of Achievement to Drs. Gasser and Rivers.
- Northern Masonic Jurisdiction - Supreme Council 33 Degree Scotish Rite, 1953-1964 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Radio Pill, 1957-1959 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Correspondence primarily with the Veterans Administration on research using "radio pill" developed at Rockefeller Institute.
- State Financial Aid, 1968-1973 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  Correspondence and reports submitted for implementation of program of aid to certain non-public institutions of higher learning.
- Strike Day at the Rockefeller University, 1970 May (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Teachers' Insurance and Annuity Association of America, 1970, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  Lists of new employees eligible to join
- Tuition Refund Plan - 1970 Survey Questionnaire (Box 1, Folder 20)
- World of Learning, 1961-1974 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  1966-1967 is not in the collection. Copies of material for edition changes.
- World Almanac, 1964-1973 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  Copies of material for edition changes.
- Rockefeller University Press, 1958-1959, 1963-1964, 1970-1974 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  File maintained by Pamela Lee.
- Civil Rights Assurances, 1964-1967, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Correspondence and printed material on or about the 1964 Civil Rights Act and compliance with it. File maintained by Pamela Lee.
- Fulbright Scholars, 1958-1963, 1965, 1971-1972, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 3)